<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Adam Li's blog - Personal</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2023</title><link href="/blog/2023/01/goals-2023/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2023-01-02:/blog/2023/01/goals-2023/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Summary of 2022&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another year has gone by and it was definitely a jam-packed year. This year, I've decided to begin organizing my yearly summaries into sections for personal, notable events, travel, health, professional-related and societal impact. Societal impact is a new one for me, where I'm trying to focus on making a net positive impact on society with my life. There is an emphasis on environmental awareness and education that I will try to abide by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned 30 years old, which seemed daunting at first, but in my opinion the best years are still ahead. I moved out of Harlem and started living in Midtown, NYC, which was honestly one of the best decisions. The apartment has made me really love living in NYC and enjoy my time here in the city. In the city, I've been fortunate to try loads of new restaurants from Hyun (all you can eat Japanese A5 Wagyu), to Kono (a Michelin star worthy Yakitori) and many more. This year, I bought tickets to different comedy clubs and shows. NYC is definitely the best city in America and lives up to its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides NYC living, some other notable mentions for this year are travel / big-events, professional developments and health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I traveled a lot this year. I attended a few big friend weddings, such as my friends (BC and AS) to going to The Yacht Week with 30 other friends. I did a lot of traveling with the K family from Atlanta all the way to Costa Rica for the holidays. I also went to LA and San Diego a few times to catch up with old friends and see Gryffin in a super-crowded LA historic park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Mammoth with my family to ski and see my newphew "try skiing" for the first time. I ended the year by playing golf for the first time with friends and the K family. I definitely sucked, but enjoyed it immensely, which will be a motivation for an updated health goal this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started becoming more active and even more health-conscious. I bought an air purifier, which I always keep on when I'm sleeping now because the air we breathe is something we take for granted. I installed water faucet filter (which has a higher filter efficacy compared to e.g. Brita) because water even in NYC is something we ingest constantly. I refined some of my vegetarian cooking dishes, such as lentils. I began running consistently thanks to my roommate and achieved a VO2 max of more than 47 (as measured by my Apple Watch). According to Apple, I've excercised an average of 72 minutes per day, with a daily walking/running distance of 6.2 miles. I also slept an average of 7 hrs and 16 minutes per day in 2022. Disclaimer: although I wear my Apple Watch consistently, I do not always have it on. Moreover, the Apple Watch series 3 and SE versions are not perfect and thus these measurements are all rough estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my professional life, I feel that this year I have been finding a balance between my personal and professional lives. I started my postdoc at Columbia University studying something completely different from my PhD. I delved more into "theory" and rigorous proofs, compared to analyzing clinical data and working with clinicians on solving applied problems. This has been a great learning experience (many thanks to one of my mentors, Adele Ribeiro) for thinking about notions of causality and how they play a role in data analysis and how they might be applied in the biomedical sciences. I'm slightly disappointed in myself for not being able to take a project to completion this year, but I think that was somewhat expected considering I pivoted my research. I am very glad I learned so much from repeatedly reading and implementing different causal inference papers. I felt that I have a very holistic understanding of causal discovery now because of the time spent rigorously reading the literature. I finished up the year being accepted as a KP Fellows 2022 Program (deferred to 2023) and being a Machine Learning Engineering Intern at Uber. I learned a lot by working on an applied project within Uber that combined causal estimation with combinatorial optimization. It gave me a glimpse of the problems that industry and academia need to tackle and solve in-order for us to have an improved causal model of the world. I also made various commits to the &lt;code&gt;dodiscover&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pywhy-graphs&lt;/code&gt; packages in &lt;code&gt;py-why&lt;/code&gt; organization. Moreover, I've made several Cython PRs into scikit-learn. I'm happy I'm still heavily involved in open-source software and plan on continuing to do so in my spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Societal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I began donating blood on a consistent basis. I've donated whole blood 4 times this year. Besides the benefits of saving a life, getting a regular iron and blood pressure checkup, donating blood consistently has been shown to reduce the levels of microplastic in our blood stream [1]. Moreover, according to the NYBC, every month, we need over 10,000 blood donations. Assuming you donate whole blood, you can only donate ~6 times per year, so this is quite a limiting factor. Finally, donating blood as an Asian increases the likelihood that another Asian who has sickle-cell disease would have a match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another theme is that I've been mentally tracking and trying to reduce my material consumption, such as reducing clothing purchases, reducing water bottle purchases/consumption, reducing usage of low-efficiency products (e.g. air purifiers without a first-stage washable filter), and attempting to re-use plastic bags, boxes, paper bags, and other materials more before finally throwing them away. In general, it was quite an eye-opener when I first learned a few years ago that recycling is essentially putting a bandaid on a gigantic wound. While it does not hurt, it certainly is not the main effort that people should focus on. Moreover, I recently learned that adding non-recyclable materials, or dirty materials (e.g. with food scraps, or unwashed containers) can actually increase the cost of recycling. So nowadays, I definitely try to be more conscious of what/how I am recylcling and overall reducing my consumption as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I'm excited for this year because I have a positive outlook and exciting plans for the upcoming years. I am eager to execute on the ideas I have for both personal and professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Old 2022 Goals:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the goals that I set out to accomplish were in the personal development and health category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;0. Communal with Partner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Sarah and I decided to set a few goals together that we can work towards both on our own, but also collectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Taking more photos.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will make an IG/photo-collage of 2022 because I have some great moments to memorialize!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Hanging out with someone new once a month.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was somewhat accomplished due to our willingness to say "yes" :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Working out in the morning (i.e. before 9AM) 3 times per week&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sadly, I am still a non-morning person. Maybe this year, we'll change it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[x] Keep VO2 max on Apple Watch 46 or above.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished this year with a current VO2 max of 47.2, which is primarily due to my new enjoyment of running and going on long walks throughout the city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Lose 10 lbs, or get a 6-pack.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think I achieved the opposite of this goal. Granted, I have a 4-pack... so maybe that's something. I definitely think this will be a goal for 2023 because I can't continue eating/gaining weight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Finish a PR into scikit-learn for oblique trees.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was started, but not even reviewed unfortunately, due to limited dev time. However, I started a series of PRs that aim at refactoring the tree base code to enable improved modularity for 3rd party extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Write JOSS paper for mne-connectivity.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I held off on this for the sake of waiting to stabilize the API and robustness of the package. I have steadily been reviewing other people's PRs though in hopes of improving community contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Write one paper with causal inference.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a work in progress now that I have an idea of the projects I can feasibly work on and accomplish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Try to code one dapp on Algorand blockchain.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not feasible for now because of my concentration in other areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Misc. / Outreach / Societal Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule an EverydayBME trip if Covid ends, possibly to Southeast Asia, China, or South America.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not possible with the current environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule 1-2 Korean classes per month through italkie (https://www.italki.com/i/ref/bDdDHD?hl=en).&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, I gave this up after 2 months. I am aiming to restart this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Get back into the habit of reading books, instead of going on Netflix. Read 3-5 books over the year.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read 2 new books: The Rosy Project and Bad Blood, but unfortunately, also stopped this. I will plan to pick this up again this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023 Goals:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;0. Communal with Partner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Spending time to maintain relationships that are important. Mindfully plan 1-2 hangouts and group activities with friend groups per month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Working out in the morning (i.e. before 9AM) 3 times per week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Keep VO2 max on Apple Watch 48 or above. Currently, my VO2 max is at a steady 47. I want to increase this ideally to 50 or above as a 30 y/o as measured by the Apple Watch SE. This can be done by consistently running, sprinting, and/or walking up hills as well as doing HIIT workouts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Register and run the Brooklyn Spring 10k in March and complete the New Yorker Half Marathon in September.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Lose 10 lbs to a steady 160 lbs, or get a 6-pack. This can be accomplished by eating healthier and minding the calories ingested per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Finish refactoring PRs for the tree submodule in scikit-learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Make two releases of the &lt;code&gt;pywhy-graphs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;dodiscover&lt;/code&gt; packages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Make and implement the &lt;code&gt;scikit-tree&lt;/code&gt; package. In this package, I will guide development of modern scikit-learn compatible tree algorithms. The result of this would be a paper on conditional mutual information estimation using unsupervised trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Write one paper with causal inference related to PAGs and optimal adjustment or causal discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Misc. / Outreach / Societal Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule 5-6 blood donations this year. As specified above, there are numerous benefits to others (and yourself) for donating blood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule 1 Chinese speaking class per month through italkie to enhance my vocabulary and phrases during conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule 1-2 Korean classes per month through italkie (https://www.italki.com/i/ref/bDdDHD?hl=en). My goal is to have a basic conversation with the K family by the end of the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Get back into the habit of reading books, instead of going on Netflix. Read 3-5 books over the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Gasiorowski R, Forbes MK, Silver G, et al. Effect of Plasma and Blood Donations on Levels of Perfluoroalkyl and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances in Firefighters in Australia: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(4):e226257. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.6257. https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2790905.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2022</title><link href="/blog/2022/01/goals-2022/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2022-01-02:/blog/2022/01/goals-2022/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Summary of 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's because I'm getting older, or maybe it's because of Covid, but the years have been passing by faster and faster. There's a lot to be thankful for this year, especially given the amount of different transitions happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of trips, I started out with a Vermont skiing trip, which turned into quite a memory when the power went out for approximately 8 hours. We had to burn firewood to keep warm and melt snow to water in order to flush a toilet. Sarah took me on a cabin trip in Severna Park, Maryland, where we stayed at a beautiful AirBnB. During the summer, we also spent a lot of time traveling. First off, we went to Yosemite with Sarah's family, which was awesome. We hiked upper Yosemite Falls, a grueling 3000 feet elevation over 7 miles. We then went to Portland for Sarah's birthday. I went to Miami to celebrate my buddy's Bachelor party and then went back to Baltimore. Afterwards, Sarah and I went back to California, going up the 101 from Thousand Oaks, Santa Barbara, Morro Bay, Monterey all the way to the Bay Area for my friend's wedding. Going back to the east coast, I made the final move into NYC. Throughout the rest of the year, Sarah and I went on a few more trips: Chicago to see Porter Robinson, and then Portugal, going through Lisbon and Porto. To top off the new years, we celebrated in New Orleans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionally, I had a lot to celebrate this year. My main PhD study was officially published in Nature Neuroscience, and moreover it was featured as the cover of the October Issue. I took a final course in constrained optimization and received my Master's degree in Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics. I applied for and got the NSF Computing Innovation Fellowship, which secured my postdoctoral research funding for two years. I also made the move to Columbia Unviersity to begin working with Dr. Elias Bareinboim on causal inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also been an active contributor in open-source, specifically MNE-BIDS, MNE-Python and MNE-Connectivity. I was accepted into the Google Summer of Code 2021 to work on MNE-Connectivity, which ported over the connectivity analysis functions from MNE-Python. As a result of my contributions, the core developers invited me to join the core dev team and the steering council. I also initiated conversations with scikit-learn core developer team to try to bring oblique trees into the scikit-learn codebase, which will probably lead to a multi-year effort due to the complexity and size of the scikit-learn codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited for this year because I'll be turning 30 and starting a new chapter in NYC and Columbia University. I'll be attempting to obtain a tenure-track faculty position, while studying causal inference as a postdoc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2021 Goals:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[X] Continue to do yoga 5 times/week for at least 5-10 minutes per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[X] Continue running at least 10 miles/week (1-4 miles per day).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[X] Begin learning how to cook vegetable only dishes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[X] SickKids dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Theory of epileptogenesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Outreach / Societal Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Volunteer at least once/month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[X] Be more mindful of re-using things (e.g. plastic, etc.). Aim to re-use things until they are broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2022 Goals:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;0. Communal with Partner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Sarah and I decided to set a few goals together that we can work towards both on our own, but also collectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Taking more photos. I want enough photos of awesome moments, so that there's a collage of photos per month (can post on IG, or some other blog form to store the photo collection)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Hanging out with someone new once a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Working out in the morning (i.e. before 9AM) 3 times per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Keep VO2 max on Apple Watch 46 or above. Aim for 47, or 48. This is the maximum volume of VO2, which is estimated on your Apple Watch. If I can hit 47, or 48 while I am in my 30's, then I'll have a high degree of cardio fitness. This will probably require me to run and swim more often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Lose 10 lbs, or get a 6-pack. While weight and body fat isn't an indicator of health, it's an easily trackable metric that can let me know if I am eating too much, or excercising too little.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Finish a PR into scikit-learn for oblique trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Write JOSS paper for mne-connectivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Write one paper with causal inference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Try to code one dapp on Algorand blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Misc. / Outreach / Societal Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule an EverydayBME trip if Covid ends, possibly to Southeast Asia, China, or South America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Schedule 1-2 Korean classes per month through italkie (https://www.italki.com/i/ref/bDdDHD?hl=en).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Get back into the habit of reading books, instead of going on Netflix. Read 3-5 books over the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2021</title><link href="/blog/2020/12/goals-2021/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-12-24:/blog/2020/12/goals-2021/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Summary of 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has been pretty blessed considering what's happening around the world with Covid-19. 
I did a cabin trip with Sarah and friends early in the year and did New Years Eve at a club seeing Kaskade(?). 
Definitely safe to say, I can't do "long" nights out anymore. 
I went to Cancun with my family and Sarah at the beginning of the year before Covid hit and 
then spent 3-4 months at the Kim family house, which was definitely... longer then expected. 
Throughout quarantine, really got to know myself better. Found an interest in gardening and 
cooking and really had to explicitly focus on mental health. In the summer, got to make a trip home 
and even go down to San Diego to see some old friends from the BodyRock/SD crew. Was very memorable 
even with Covid restrictions, and happy I went. In the midst of Covid, got to experience 
July 4th still with some NYC friends up near Westpoint. Closer to Halloween, 
saw K-Town in Manhattan with all its outdoor seating! It was actually quite awesome, 
and something I hope they keep during all the non-winter months in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAMPLIFY managed to get through the pandemic by shifting its gears to a virtual 
summer program. It actually was quite successful and I was glad to introduce a 
statistical and data-driven thinking portion to the leadership curriculum. EverydayBME
managed to shift gears in the face of the pandemic as well. We partnered with BMESDiversity and 
offered Patagonia 1/4 zips to entice a social media display of the diversity in BME 
science and research. It was actually quite awesome to see how many minority groups 
participated because it speaks to some of the successes at least we've had in the BME
community in terms of diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the start of the Fall semester, my paper was accepted for
review at a high-profile journal, which was a really nice touch (we'll see 
if it gets accepted though heh). In addition, I managed to work with a 
small team (many talented individuals) to get an EEG analytics software in 
its MVP version approved by the FDA via a 510k approval process. Learned a lot about 
regulatory and how to work with the FDA and consultants to get a software approved. Finally, 
I took a very interesting course, called Real Variables with Professor Sogge at JHU. Learned a lot 
about Lebesgue measure, integration and differentiation theory. In addition, got a 
very nice introduction to Hilbert spaces and Fourier series, integrals, transforms. 
Wish I took the course 3 years earlier. I've also been an active contributor in open-source 
and was later added to the BIDS-standard team by Stefan. I've really become amazed by 
the open-source community. I've had lengthy Github conversations with many talented individuals 
that I've never even met, let alone know their face, or voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's important to reflect on how "blessed" this year was for myself, but also 
reflect on some of the bad that came with it. This year marked the onset of the Covid-19 
pandemic, and with it, many many people were forced to stay home. An aggregation of poor response, 
and misinformation led to the pandemic bringing the USA to its knees. When we look at countries 
like South Korea, Taiwan, New Zealand, Vietnam and more, it's quite apparent what differences there 
were to anyone that is scientifically trained. In addition, at the same time, we saw the 
very public unnecessary deaths of many Black Americans (Ahmaud Arbery, Breonna Taylor and George Floyd 
to name a few). For people like me that live in a world of first-world privilege, it probably 
"shocked" us. I know for me at least, it really started making me question the society we live in and 
what sort of biases I've been engraved with since childhood. It also was hard to come to terms with 
the fact that this kind of thing has been honestly happening far too frequently since before I 
was even born. It is a flaw in how we are taught history, and a flaw in our society. 
With the poor pandemic response, and racial problems of the USA, it is apparent that 
voting strong local public officials that are knowledgeable, scientifically driven and 
socially aware is more important then we realize. Going to be on the lookout for more ways I can 
actively, or passively help as time progresses. I'm glad that I was also able to at least do a bit 
more research in my local, state and federal elections then I normally would in the hope that I become 
a responsible and socially aware voter beyond just this year. A side effect of the pandemic actually 
made me do more reading and research into climate change and being a "green citizen". It 
took me by surprise that recycling is more nuanced then just use, recycle, reuse. Projecting 
forward decades, it was became more apparent to me that we can't keep living the way we do - 
taking from the earth without thought. It actually will lead to more racial inequality and 
potentially cause more social issues that we can't even imagine. Part of my personal 
goals for this new year is to become a more "green citizen", as well as being a 
"responsible socially aware citizen".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2020 Goals:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Health: (Half-Marathon)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;13.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Longer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;ve ever ran in my life, but it&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;going&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;goal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;entrance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;adulthood&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;In&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;point&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;say&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Boston&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;half&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;marathon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;October&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2020&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;there&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;will&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;decent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;amount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;training&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;involved&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;should&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;goal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;per&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;March&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;per&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;June&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Boston&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;June&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;training&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;July&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;half&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;marathon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;Learn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;another&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;few&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;signature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;dishes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;maintain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cooking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pancetta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;wrapped&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;stuffed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;chicken&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;fetta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cheese&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;spinach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mushrooms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;garlic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;wine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;dish&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;X&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;fresh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pasta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;dish&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely could have ran more this year, but because of Covid, I've "exercised" less, but 
have been running significantly more. I've gone up to ~4 mile runs every now and then, but 
am nowhere close to a half-marathon level. Cooking-wise, Sarah and I have explored 
many many dishes, such as: eggplant lasagna, medium-rare rib-eye steak, indian marinated chicken, 
thigh curry chicken, fresh-made linguini with seafood and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Professional:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;Internship, or open-source development with at least 10 closed Issues and Pull Requests.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I haven't done an internship as I was hoping, I have been significantly more active 
in open-source. I've contributed to &lt;a href="https://github.com/mne-tools/mne-bids"&gt;mne-bids&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/mne-tools/mne-python"&gt;mne-python&lt;/a&gt;,
the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bids-standard/bids-specification"&gt;BIDS specification&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/bids-standard/bids-validator"&gt;bids-validator&lt;/a&gt;, 
and many more. Open source science rocks! I believe I've definitely gone beyond 10 closed Issues/PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Personal:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;Think before speaking more, patience and focus on my friends, family and significant other more then myself. I&amp;#39;ve focused on my self-growth over the last 10 years, and it&amp;#39;s time to focus on my external-growth over these next 10 years.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;I should check up on my family more often via WeChat, and give better presents for the birthday and holidays.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've done this relatively well, considering we grew up not "giving presents" normally. 
Since I'm very "calendar-oriented", it helps that I have all my birthdays and important events 
on my google calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;I should check up on my friends that don&amp;#39;t live in Baltimore every few weeks or so. Put things on the schedule for hanging out. I should invite a few friends to do Montreal with me in the summer.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven't really had an opportunity to do this as much as I would've liked. However, 
due to Covid, I've definitely had a few Zoom get-togethers ranging from catchups, to board games
to playing Among Us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;I should focus on listening to Sarah more this year. She&amp;#39;s more right then I am in more instances then I would prefer to admit. The fallacy of trying to believe in yourself is that you convince yourself out of hubris that you are right even when you are wrong.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could probably do better here still. I think I've been marginally improving, but there 
can be more instances where I reflect more on my thought patterns and actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Goals 2021:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I've found that mental and physical health are intricately linked. In addition, they 
have consequences on professional productivity. Sarah introduced me to yoga this year, and I 
actually quite enjoy it since it involves a lot of stretching, deep breaths and movements 
that I otherwise wouldn't do. It's a great way to be active in the morning and after runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other activities I've found helpful are running and cooking healthy. Cooking isn't just healthy, 
but it is a relaxing activity. In addition, now that I'm more comfortable cooking, I want 
to explore more by cooking healthy. Cooking healthy means cooking with just vegetables and 
ingredients that are not currently being stressed by human activity (e.g. red meat, 
fish, fat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Continue to do yoga 5 times/week for at least 5-10 minutes per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Continue running at least 10 miles/week (1-4 miles per day).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Begin learning how to cook vegetable only dishes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Professional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This upcoming year, I'll be graduating with my PhD and MS from Johns Hopkins. 
I'm looking forward to taking courses in constrained optimization, stochastic 
optimization and graph theory. I'll also probably be starting a transition to a 
post doc, or industry position. In order to feel like my PhD is fulfilled, I would 
like to publish a few more projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] SickKids dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Theory of epileptogenesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Outreach / Societal Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I would also like to dedicate more time to outreach. I think there's 
too often change that could be done at the local volunteer level that isn't because 
of passiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Volunteer at least once/month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] Be more mindful of re-using things (e.g. plastic, etc.). Aim to re-use things 
until they are broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2020</title><link href="/blog/2020/01/goals-2020/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-01:/blog/2020/01/goals-2020/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year was a great way to end what I like to call a decade of growth. These past 10 years, I went from high school to college. I found out the things I love, the things I hate and the things that I could care less about. Love came and went, along with different friends. Above all else, I am almost certain that I've found what I love to do. Science, and the ability to "make discoveries" that can help people are what I hope to do for the rest of my life. I came to graduate school without understanding why I wanted to be there, and where I wanted to go, but now I'm getting ready to leave... at least understanding why I came. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I am glad I found a partner that has been supportive of what I do, and patient enough to listen to my weird and obnoxious thoughts on things ranging from sleeping habits, to science. It has and should continue to be a thrilling experience to make mistakes, reflect and adapt while I face the next challenge of learning how to grow two minds at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm close to graduating from school where I will never have to "take courses" again, but rather then rejoicing that I never have to set foot in a classroom again, I'm realizing I'll miss the lessons in logic you learn from challenging yourself through homework and exams. I took up the Masters in AMS at JHU this year, and I'm glad I went through with it. I am close to publishing most of my thesis work this year and then going through the final defense of the PhD. It didn't seem so far away that I was struggling to understand the basic methodological papers my undergrad PI sent me, but now I'm confident to say that I at least understand 50% of things with a one time read. Time to grow and reflect on this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2019 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Learning Mandarin Chinese - Simplified [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Traveling to a Mandarin speaking country, Taiwan with my friends made me realize my Chinese is horrendous. I always went to China with my family, and I never had to get around by myself. This was the first time I wanted to rely on my Chinese to communicate with strangers, and get around the country, but I realized my speaking and reading ability is just not up to par. This year, I'm committed to speaking to my parents in as much Chinese as possible and I've even started a Wechat/Messenger/Line group chat with my Chinese friends to practice Chinese."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah this stopped after April when my friends Anthony and Justin stopped using Line chat lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Bartending Basic Drinks and Theory [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a bartending kit on Amazon and am aiming to learn how to make some basic drinks like an old fashioned, mojito and other drinks I can find online. Aiming to learn how to make 6 good drinks by the years end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely instead of doing this, I chose to not drink as much, ... so I guess that's an accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Continuation of Lifestyle Changes [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Cutting my own hair, benching 2 plates, reaching deadlift of 3 plates and running at least 5 miles per week. Been proud of myself for learning how to cut my own hair (thus saving time and money each month), and hitting a bench press of 2 plates, while still weighing 160 lbs. This year I hope to continue my fitness goals and potentially shave off 10-15 lbs to a flat 145-150 lb. This will be achieved with the help of my nifty Apple Watch Series 3."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still been cutting hair, but went all in on the high-rep, 1 plate for bench, deadlift and squat. I've been running a lot more recently and I think that will lead me to the goal-setting of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Professional Improvements and Consolidation of Technical Skills [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managed to get a lot of things done this year :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Improving Photography With New IG Page [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This year, I'm going to try to post new photos to a new instagram blog page with more travel related photos. This is to sort of separate my personal instagram from my photography hobby. I have a lot more to learn about optimal lighting and photography of different scenes (e.g. portraits, landscapes, nightshots). I am aiming to post an additional 12 photos that I am proud of onto this IG page by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link to keep up to dates with my adventure!
https://www.instagram.com/ajltravels/
"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn't happen as much as I wanted, but instead I worked with a few colleagues to get @EverydayBME off the ground, which is a super cool Instagram page off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2020 Goals:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Health: (Half-Marathon)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13.1 miles. Longer then I've ever ran in my life, but it's going to be the goal of this year, and the entrance into adulthood. In order to get to this point, say for the Boston half-marathon on October 13, 2020, then there will be a decent amount of training involved. I should set a goal to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] run 1-2 times per week with 4+ miles by March. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] run 1-2 times per week with 6+ miles by June. Run the Boston 10k in June.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[ ] and then start training in July for the half-marathon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I measure side-effect success? Heart rate should ideally go to resting at 50 consistently. I should be stretching consistently and doing foam rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn another few signature dishes to maintain cooking health :).
- [ ] pancetta wrapped stuffed chicken w/ fetta cheese, spinach, mushrooms and garlic
- [ ] a red wine dish
- [ ] a fresh pasta dish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Professional:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internship, or open-source development with at least 10 closed Issues and Pull Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Personal:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think before speaking more, patience and focus on my friends, family and significant other more then myself. I've focused on my self-growth over the last 10 years, and it's time to focus on my external-growth over these next 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should check up on my family more often via WeChat, and give better presents for the birthday and holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should check up on my friends that don't live in Baltimore every few weeks or so. Put things on the schedule for hanging out. I should invite a few friends to do Montreal with me in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should focus on listening to Sarah more this year. She's more right then I am in more instances then I would prefer to admit. The fallacy of trying to believe in yourself is that you convince yourself out of hubris that you are right even when you are wrong. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Europe - Living and Traveling</title><link href="/blog/2018/06/europe-summary-2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-01:/blog/2018/06/europe-summary-2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of my time abroad in Europe, 2017-2018.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick Background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top Experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture EU vs America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Quick Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year, I was fortunate to live in France, Europe from September 2017 till August 2018. While, I couldn't speak much French, I worked in an english speaking laboratory at Aix-Marseille Universite, under a really talented and successful professor, Dr. Viktor Jirsa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there, I had the chance to visit numerous countries and cities (I try to stay chronologically):
- London, UK
- Munich, Germany (Oktoberfest)
- Casablanca and Marrakech, Morocco
- Budapest, Hungary
- Geneva/Lausanne, Switzerland (LauzHack)
- Lyon, France
- Prague, Czech Republic
- Paris, France (Thanksgiving)
- Munich, Germany (with parents)
- Vienna, Austria
- London, UK (Christmas)
- Zurich, Switzerland (NY)
- Cambridge, UK (Cambridge Hacks)
- Berlin, Germany (Bosch Connected World Hackathon/Conference)
- Amsterdam, Netherlands (SD friends here)
- Paris, France
- Cassis, France (from Marseille)
- Amsterdam, Netherlands (Baltimore friends here)
- Barcelona, Spain
- Paris, France
- Saint Raphael, France (For TNG/INS Retreat! So fun...)
- Monaco
- Nice, France
- London -&amp;gt; Dublin, Ireland 
- Lisbon and Porto, Portugal
- London, UK (Last layover before heading home to USA)
- Tuscany and Pisa, Italy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Top Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switzerland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Southern France&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traveling A Lot
TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Culture EU vs America&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture in Europe is a huge mix of different nations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America is different because we are one nation with a mix of many nationalities that came to solely LIVE in America. Honestly, we're all American. I felt more American while living abroad, then Chinese because that's who I am; that's how I grew up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics of America in Europe is actually very well known. Everyone I knew heard about the major events in the USA. They knew a lot about Trump's policies and found it amusing that Americans had so many divisive issues that were not present in EU life. For example, they found it absurd that we have guns. Even if it is for enjoyment..., why do we need them? Even if you're a law-abiding citizen, why do you need a gun. EU citizens definitely don't see America as a great country in any aspect since Trump got elected. Most of the times the USA came up, it was with an air of humor, or mockery. To be fair, I agreed at times with them because Trump acted like a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Misc.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we share this interview in our social media posts?
Would you be okay with us writing small posts that may highlight different parts of this interview? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the most memorable part of your experience abroad?
(Telling a story and highlights of doing research abroad in an intl setting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;traveling, connecting with people from other countries and going on a lab retreat EU style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the Whitaker experience improve your research in graduate school?
(relating their exp back to the Whitaker program)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it brought a different viewpoint into my research of epilepsy seizure localization. It also exposed me to the field of computational modeling and using dynamical systems to study biological phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For scientists planning on going abroad for a prolonged visit, what is some advice you would give them?
(giving some value to readers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;spend as much time as you can engaging in other researchers while you are there. Take as much time as you can to travel within the country and region also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you explain the research you undertook during your Whitaker in laymen terms and why it was important?
(education about the research to the general public that is digestable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simulating seizures in the brain to determine if algorithms designed on empirical data can localize the origin of these seizures in-silico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="europe"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2019</title><link href="/blog/2018/01/goals-2019/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-01-07:/blog/2018/01/goals-2019/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year has passed, and its getting harder and harder for me to distinguish the years from each other. Every new years goals post seems to be written just a few days ago in my head. This year was filled with transitions, both personal and professional. I started off the year living in France, and traveling to Switzerland to see how a NYE abroad would be like. The time abroad up until August was an experience that really taught me how to survive in a completely different country without a cohort of students around me, or a friend group from college for support. I did a lot of traveling in Europe, seeing countries and cities that I've never been to, such as Hungary, Portugal, Morocco and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionally, I grew in ways that I did not expect. Rather then going to the EMBC conference with the rest of my lab, I went to a computationally focused neuroscience conference in Seattle. I reconnected with my high school friends and some old friends from JHU. The time there was perfect and a fond way for me to transition my life back into the USA. My time spent with the Theoretical Neurosciences Group helped me grow as an independent thinker and researcher. I developed a distinct appreciation for how mathematics can drive precise and beautiful descriptions of biological systems. I did some explicit exploration of using deep learning to understand its classification capabilities, and also see the pitfalls that occur when designing an architecture, or training scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2018 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Travel [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I traveled a lot last year. Currently this year, I've visited London, Paris, Lyon, Marrackech, Casablanca, Munich, Vienna, Prague, Budapest, Lausanne, Geneva, Cambridge, Nice, Monaco, Barcelona, Amsterdam, Lisbon, Porto, Tuscany, Qatar, Seoul, Busan, Hanoi, Lanhah Bay, Ho Chi Minh City and Columbus (Ohio). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my travel goals for this year are two parts:
i. I'm going to try to visit:
Lisbon [ ], 
Oslo [ ], 
Helsinki [ ], 
Stockholm [ ], 
Istanbul [ ], 
Athens [ ], 
Santorini [ ],
Croatia [ ], 
Luxembourg [ ], 
Bordeaux [ ], 
Berlin [ ], 
Frankfurt [ ], 
Rome [ ] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. The things I'm going to try to attend are Tomorrowland 2018 [ ] and Yacht week 2018 [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Academic [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I submitted a conference paper on using research I did in France, using a computational modeling platform to study algorithmic performance of seizure localization in epilepsy patients. I submitted a poster for some preliminary work on combining training from empirical data and simulated data to improve seizure detection. This was a completely independent idea that I only had after spending some time working in France. I enrolled in Matrix Theory when I got back to JHU and really enjoyed delving deeper into the mathematical theory behind matrices and linear algebra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year holds a lot of potential. I'll be submitting a journal paper for a complete retrospective study on the fragility algorithm [ ], which will be part of my main thesis work. I'm going to be enrolled in Linear Systems Theory to understand more theory behind our work in the NCSL lab. I will also attempt to audit an optimization course with a focus on theory to better understand some of the core optimization algorithms that take place in machine learning and statistical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Professional [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to submit applications for internships, but I feel like research is always going on and interrupting the flow of things. My goal here was to submit applications to DE Shaw LLC, DE Shaw Research, Google Brain Research Team, DeepMind, Facebook Research, Amazon Data Science, Amazon Health Research. In all fairness, things were hectic with life as I had to transition between living in France back to JHU. I can still do this, but I hope that I can achieve that this fall, when things have settled at JHU and my PhD is nearing its end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python review of data structures [ ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math review of machine learning basics, such as backpropagation, convolutional networks, lstm network, logistic regression, linear regression, expectation maximization scheme [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Personal [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wanted to do more photography, but my camera got stolen halfway into the year (RIP). However, I splurged and got an even better setup! The Sony a6500, will hopefully allow me to go even further with night shots, portraits and landscapes during this year. Also managed to hit benching of 225.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to reach a 
- a deadlift of 275 [ ] and 
- consistent running of 1-5 miles (by the end of the year) [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Cooking and Lifestyle [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed to start cooking a lot in France. Once I returned to JHU, I started cooking pretty lean at nighttime with a spinach, salmon and chicken breast with garlic combinations. I also started making kale smoothies on a daily routine, which has been a life changer. Who knew pumping your body with greens and some ginger in the morning, concealed with the sugar of frozen fruits would feel and taste so good?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Reading and Knowledge [X]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've tried to take on more reading about new topics that I find interesting, such as politics and blockchain technologies. I started using Pocket, which is a great resource for saving webpages for easy reading offline at a later time! Will continue to do so on topics related to blockchain scaling, right and left-wing politics, and machine learning in industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resolutions for 2019:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Learning Mandarin Chinese - Simplified [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling to a Mandarin speaking country, Taiwan with my friends made me realize my Chinese is horrendous. I always went to China with my family, and I never had to get around by myself. This was the first time I wanted to rely on my Chinese to communicate with strangers, and get around the country, but I realized my speaking and reading ability is just not up to par. This year, I'm committed to speaking to my parents in as much Chinese as possible and I've even started a Wechat/Messenger/Line group chat with my Chinese friends to practice Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Bartending Basic Drinks and Theory [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a bartending kit on Amazon and am aiming to learn how to make some basic drinks like an old fashioned, mojito and other drinks I can find online. Aiming to learn how to make 6 good drinks by the years end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Continuation of Lifestyle Changes [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting my own hair, benching 2 plates, reaching deadlift of 3 plates and running at least 5 miles per week. Been proud of myself for learning how to cut my own hair (thus saving time and money each month), and hitting a bench press of 2 plates, while still weighing 160 lbs. This year I hope to continue my fitness goals and potentially shave off 10-15 lbs to a flat 145-150 lb. This will be achieved with the help of my nifty Apple Watch Series 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Professional Improvements and Consolidation of Technical Skills [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I'll be making a lot of strides in my professional career. On one hand, I'll be pursuing the development of a startup company that is a result of my PhD research. My PI and I will be developing a seizure localization software that outperforms anything on the market, or in academic research. Interestingly it is not based on deep learning ;). This means that I will have the opportunity to actually experience developing and designing software that complies with a 510K FDA approved software device. The software must be usable by clinicians, which will involve production level coding in Python. I look forward to learning while developing with our software engineering consultants (who definitely know more about production level coding). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the ideal goal is to be able to sell our technology by the years end to a larger EEG based company who can scale and distribute the technology into the clinic fast. Even if this doesn't happen, I believe there are still many important lessons to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this endeavor, I aim to showcase to myself and others that I am capable of designing and implementing a production level software system that can sit in a clinical center that pulls data, formats data properly, preprocesses it, runs an optimized parallelized algorithm for analysis and outputs high-grade visualizations that are clinically useful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I want to practice more of my coding skills with data structures and basic algorithms using LeetCode. So far, I've done 20-30 exercises and they are actually quite interesting to sit through. Upon reading the solutions, I always learn something new in terms of how to think like an experienced programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Improving Photography With New IG Page [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I'm going to try to post new photos to a new instagram blog page with more travel related photos. This is to sort of separate my personal instagram from my photography hobby. I have a lot more to learn about optimal lighting and photography of different scenes (e.g. portraits, landscapes, nightshots). I am aiming to post an additional 12 photos that I am proud of onto this IG page by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See link to keep up to dates with my adventure!
https://www.instagram.com/ajltravels/&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2018</title><link href="/blog/2017/12/goals-2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-12-31:/blog/2017/12/goals-2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year has been a fantastic year from beginning to end. I turned the big 2 5 (yay 1 year older). However, this year came with a lot of fun as I spent time at Coachella 2017, made it out for birthdays of my friends in Vegas, spent time in SF, LA, SD and Chicago visiting old friends, enjoyed new time with Hopkins friends in NYC, Boston and DC, and spent a lot of time enjoying my "relative" last year in Baltimore. I was fortunate enough to win three prestigious fellowships: the NSF-GRFP, Whitaker and Chateaubriand fellowships. I presented two conference papers at two different conferences, where I was even able to make a trip through Korea and Japan come out of it. It's ending with me being in France working with the Theoretical Neurosciences Group in Marseille. I am incredibly fortunate to be working in a group of extraordinary people from all different countries and backgrounds. I am learning so much and developing new ideas that I honestly can't say I would've had if I were just back in Baltimore. I think I have some explicit goals this year related to my work because I find it fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2017 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Keep dance a significant part of my life: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is actually something I thought would impact me a lot. I still watch hella dance vids online and keep up with hip hop news here and there, but I haven't touched the dance floor in a few months and it almost feels normal now. I get my daily exercise and I'm driven by my research and learning opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Run a half-marathon: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah I don't know if this will ever happen... So maybe I'll aim to do a 5k next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Read four new books: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always learn from others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Establish a healthy workout regimen: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got to be able to deadlift 245, and bench 205 this year. I've also started working out in the morning, or at least daily. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Put myself in uncomfortable situations: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I moved to France and have been traveling my ass off. I don't intend on stopping and I've found that I started to become more comfortable with just being by myself. You really learn a lot when you have to handle everything from beginning to end without a friend/family member watching your back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Begin to learn French: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Duolingo and got to 2% fluency. Hell yeah. Well... I'm in France, so I started now LOL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Keep learning more "unrelated" math: [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was so set on the idea of data science last year, but it's all related to my interest in medicine, tech, and AI. I've been reading more papers here and there about random things ranging from deep neural networks, matrix perturbation theory, to deep reinforcement learning. None directly relate to my rsearch, but it's fascinating and great to think about how it can continue to impact my research and future growth as a data scientist / engineer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Build 3 Node, JS, React webapps this year [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah I don't know why I thought this was feasible during a PhD. However, I've built a Node.js/D3.js web app at Lauz Hack this year! I'll be building my skills further as I design a complete system for data input, data analysis and data visualization for clinical usage within a Phase I clinical trial, that I will be helping lead in the next few years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2018 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Travel [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be spending another 6-9 months in Marseille, France. I truly enjoy having this opportunity to live in Europe for not just one semester, but one year. However, I don't think I will ever choose to live here long term, so I want to take advantage of the majority of the time I have left here and go traveling... A LOT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently this year, I've visited London, Paris, Lyon, Marrackech, Casablanca, Munich, Vienna, Prague, Budapest, Lausanne, Geneva, Cambridge, Oxford, Whales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my travel goals for this year are two parts:
i. I'm going to try to visit:
Lisbon [ ], 
Oslo [ ], 
Helsinki [ ], 
Stockholm [ ], 
Nice [ ], 
Monaco [ ], 
Istanbul [ ], 
Athens [ ], 
Santorini [ ],
Croatia [ ], 
Barcelona [ ], 
Amsterdam [ ], 
Luxembourg [ ], 
Bordeaux [ ], 
Berlin [ ], 
Frankfurt [ ], 
Rome [ ], 
Bologna [ ], &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii. The things I'm going to try to attend are Tomorrowland 2018 [ ] and Yacht week 2018 [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Academic [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been able to finish two conference papers, and a journal paper as first author. I've also served as an author on two additional conference papers. This upcoming year, I want to delve deeper into the intersection of my current work with machine learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to submit two conference papers: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on initial results of fragility tested on TVB and [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initial results of a DNN tested on TVB for seizure detection. [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to submit a journal paper for a complete retrospective study on the fragility algorithm [ ] and an Bayesian inference implementation of the final layer of prediction of the EZ set. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to enroll in a class on Matrix Theory, Stochastic Optimization and Nonlinear Optimization. These are three topics I feel like I have to understand at a deeper level to fundamentally be able to tackle many generic problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Professional [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the time is approaching when I will be thinking about graduation from the PhD program at JHU. It feels like a lifetime ago that I was a nervous wreck joining JHU and wondering if I was smart enough to keep up with some of the cutting edge research in BME. I think I still have some issues with where I feel in terms of knowledge. My goal is to augment and seal up those weaknesses / shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got my short term eyes set on a few companies and positions that I have heard great things about. I am excited at the possibility of learning even more by joining mathematics, free-thinking, machine learning and data expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal here is to submit applications to DE Shaw LLC, DE Shaw Research, Google Brain Research Team, DeepMind, Facebook Research, Amazon Data Science, Amazon Health Research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in order to make it within these groups, I should develop my fundamental computer science skills further by creating in C++ and Python the various data structures and Cracking the Code Interview problem sets. I should have a fundamental understanding of backpropagation, optimization, probability, statistics, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ review of data structures [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python review of data structures [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math review of backpropagation [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math review of machine learning basics [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Personal [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've picked up photography and I enjoy just posting on Instagram/Facebook, photos that I take, that I like. I've stopped dancing, but I've started working out on a consistent basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to reach a 
- bench of 225 [ ], 
- a deadlift of 275 [ ] and 
- consistent running of 1-5 miles (by the end of the year) [ ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Cooking and Lifestyle [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be cooking at least 5 times a week, so that I can maintain a healthy diet. I will look at maintaining a combination of recipes and learning something new every other month! I'll keep an update here on the recipes I learn and experiment with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken Breast [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steak [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pasta With Meat [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salmon Dish [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuna Dish [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Fish Dish [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(if possible): Other seafood [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Reading and Knowledge [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to continuously be reading from highly regarded sources. I want to conssistently read from sources on Twitter, The World Economic Review and Bloomberg. I'll try to update some of my thoughts on the different mechanisms of obtaining knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep up with my intake of knowledge, I want to challenge myself to write a series of publicly available blog posts on trends in technology, medicine, politics and economics/finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bitcoin [X]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ethereum/blockchain [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;machine learning/AI [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;politics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foreign markets (EU/Asia) and cryptocurrency/blockchains [ ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emerging markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2017</title><link href="/blog/2016/12/goals-2017/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-12-31:/blog/2016/12/goals-2017/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on one of the best years ever, I'm grateful for all the people and places that made these memories happen. I took some time around 1 year ago to plan out ten things I wanted to carry out in 2016. I've enjoyed it a lot because it's been a goal to work towards for the entire year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I want to look at what I set out to do, and where I've come in regards to those goals. It will be interesting to see how my own priorities simply a year ago changed throughout the year and what I want to keep and discard for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old 2016 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Spend more effort and time on good friends and ignore the rest. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Definitely did it with Vegas trips, Coachella, Asia traveling, San Francisco, Chicago and New York City. All were done with great friends that I would take a bullet for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Read more about politics and current events in our country. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-I think this year was a turmoil in the United States with Donald Trump having been elected. Personally, I was spurred to follow and read more news through Twitter, Facebook and news journal sites. Although I have yet to become an expert, it has definitely exposed me to thought leaders ranging from Democratic/Republican leaders to news journalists to high ranking company executives. I've begun formulating my own thoughts on the topic (which I won't go into) and I think it's really helped me think about what I want for my future, my family's future, my children's future and my country's future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Start choreographing again. [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Totally did not do this. Will have to put this on a higher priority list this year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Enter in 1-2 jams. [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hurt my ankle during the time frame when I could've definitely entered the jam at Johns Hopkins. I'm pretty disappointed though that I didn't try to do more while it was summer time and I was still relatively free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Begin taking photos and videos more during the year and documenting them. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I definitely had a late start this year by only doing this towards the end of 2016, but I'm definitely getting more into it. I've learned the basics of manipulating aperture, shutter speed and angles. It's really fun and I'm surprised by how excited I get over good photos and photo opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Continue blogging about graduate school and the milestones of a PhD in STEM. [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think logging experiences in graduate school are important, but more important are reaching those milestones. I've realized how tough different aspects of the PhD are and I think for 2017 I would want to focus more effort on tangibly meeting milestones in graduate school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Run a half-marathon: Rock &amp;amp; Roll Half Marathon in SD/DC [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got lazy and then my ankle got hurt, but I definitely want to try again for 2017!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Spend less time on myself and volunteer more. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-I don't think I've done this at all, but in a different interpretation I've focused more on making an impact outside of research. I'm very excited to say that I started HEME (Hopkins Engineering Medicine Exchange) with one of my close friends in graduate school and I have big dreams for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;9. Spend less time on social media (Facebook and Snapchat). [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't do a great job towards the beginning because I think as all millennials are, I was addicted to seeing how other people's lives were progressing. However, simply today, one of my good friends showed me a video I think is worth sharing. (https://www.facebook.com/deltaprotective/videos/10157890106040640/?hc_ref=NEWSFEED) I want to spend even less time by keeping "Kill News Feed" and using Instagram/Facebook simply to log photographs I take and memories I want to engrave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Be content with paying my dues. [x]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think this year I started to examine what excites me in life and what excites me about the future. It definitely isn't working at some corporate 9-5 job (even if I think the job is "impactful"). It's innovating and pushing the bounds of medicine using engineering, mathematics and computer programming. These topics are what excite me, while medicine is what spurs me to make a difference. I'm looking forward to spending ~5 (hopefully) years at Johns Hopkins absorbing different learning experiences and getting my Masters in Applied Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics while I'm also there. Why not get a free additional education with the PhD while I'm there?
6/10 kinda. I guess not bad :p.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New 2017 Resolutions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Keep dance a significant part of my life: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I might not be able to choreograph a piece, participate in jams and get involved in dance photography, I want to simply keep bboying, keep taking choreo classes and keep my camera/gopro at all major dance events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Run a half-marathon: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to start running couple miles at the gym every other day and hopefully do one in the spring :).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Read four new books: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This year, I've managed to read ~4 books due to a book club established with my friends and I. It's made me more engaged in my own self development because I spent less time on social media and video games before sleeping. I want to do it again with or withoutanother book club.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Establish a healthy workout regimen: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been exercising at the gym more this year and I'm pretty happy with where I've gotten. I think being able to deadlift 245 and bench 225 are solid goals to have for this year. While continuing dancing, I hope to live a healthier lifestyle. In addition, this could entail just eating healthier through (salad every other day and cooking most nights that I have time).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Put myself in uncomfortable situations: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think this last one encompasses a number of things I think I need to go through. Although my friend circles aren't the same in Baltimore as in California, there are people I meet everyday that offer unique perspectives. Engaging in making relations is the first one. I haven't really explored doing "activities" for fun, such as hiking and exploring. I want to put myself out there and go on more "naturey" activities. I've had a lot of fun doing that in the past couple of months and I think it will only improve when I go into 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Begin to learn French: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using duolingo and trying to put myself out there with possibly a solo adventure to Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Keep learning more "unrelated" math: [ ]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In my research I have a very focused area that I am developing, but I want to become a thought leader in data science one day. The only way to do that is to continue my reading of papers unrelated to my research and continue my textbook reading of different topics, such as matrix theory and bayesian statistics. The more I understand, the more I might even be able to apply to my PhD research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Build 3 Node, JS, React webapps this year&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping it under 10 this year because I recently read about Warren Buffet's 5/25 rule and am inspired by its logic. Happy 2017 everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Goals - 2016</title><link href="/blog/2015/12/goals-2016/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Adam Li</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-12-31:/blog/2015/12/goals-2016/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A summary of goals for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Each year passes by faster and faster in my opinion, so I want to make the most out of 2016.As 2016 comes and 2015 comes to a close, I want to make some resolutions and goals for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend more effort and time on good friends and ignore the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about politics and current events in our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that coming from California is a blessing in many ways. However, I think that we take for granted all the things we have. There is a lot of different things happening around the country (e.g. politics) that I did not educate myself on. Using politico and pulse apps to keep up to date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start choreographing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout undergrad, I made excuses for not trying more in dance to improve. Whether it was coursework, social life, or laziness, I didn't put in time and effort into my passion. Will try to do at least 1 piece and work on it throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter in 1-2 jams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been bboying for almost 8 years and it has carried me through undergrad and high school. Want to continue going for top 8 in some big jams until I can't bboy anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin taking photos and videos more during the year and documenting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad gave me his old Nikon D5000 and I got a GoPro at the beginning of the summer. Photography is a way for me to keep involved in the hip hop scene once I can't dance anymore. Videos and photos are also great of documenting the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue blogging about graduate school and the milestones of a PhD in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of challenges and obstacles to overcome to get to a PhD program. There are also many to overcome whilst in the program. I want to talk about various events including: preparing for grad school in undergrad, applying for grad school, applying for fellowships, picking your rotations, picking your coursework, picking your advisor, choosing a thesis committee, structuring and studying for your DBO and then research on a daily basis. My goal is to graduate from this PhD as soon as possible (ideally 4-5 years) and start working to get industry experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run a half-marathon: Rock &amp;amp; Roll Half Marathon in SD/DC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been saying that I wanna do this for years... time to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend less time on myself and volunteer more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent too much time saying I wanna help out and not enough time doing. Getting involved in THREAD at Baltimore is one step and I hope to do more. The world is too big to just always be working on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend less time on social media (Facebook and Snapchat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good for seeing friends and chatting. Good for sending some updates once in awhile and documenting photos/videos. Not good for productivity. Aim: go from online once/day to once/two days this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be content with paying my dues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've always been anxious to accomplish things. However, over the next 4 years, I realized it'll be grind and work. Gaining the technical skills so I can set myself up for maximizing the probability of succeeding in a technical startup. Just have to be patient and have this same dream when I'm 29.
All resolutions are goals in my opinion. The only real way to accomplish a goal that you set your mind to is work on them in minimal increments. Happy new years. It's going to be a good one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="goals"></category></entry></feed>